# **Andres Arredondo Hernandez**

# Java Developer

#### **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with 5 years of experience and knowledge in software development working in the Information Technology area, in languages such as Java, Scala, JavaScript, and React as well as APIs, Git, and UML. My tenacious and proactive results in product development, and my goal-oriented attitude led to focus and time management efficiently, and other skills include fast learning, leadership, teamwork, problem solver, and creativity, both working as a team player as well as an individual worker. I have been involved in the different stages and functions corresponding to the software development cycle. I've found my biggest strength in the areas of analysis, design, and management, with a focus on the user's needs.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

• Java • Scala • Gosu • Spring Boot • Git • SQL • Oracle • My SQL • RabbitMQ • Angular 8 • Linux • Junit • Rest •React •AWS •Docker •Python •JavaScript

### **SOFT SKILLS**

- Good interpersonal skills
- Strong oral and written communication skills
- Able to work under high pressure.
- Strategically and effectively learning new concepts and technologies
- Good attention to detail
- Good organizational and problem-solving skills
- Effective time management

### **EDUCATION**

Systems Engineer / Fundación de educación superior San José

### **Certifications**

- EFSET English Certificate 67/100 (C1 Advanced) EF Standard English Test (EF SET)
- Functional Programming with Scala Platzi
- Java Persistence Platzi
- Java OOP Platzi
- Professional Course Git Platzi

#### **WORKING EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS**

### March 2022 - Current

## **Application Developer / Team Leader**

### **Company: FPT Software**

### Responsibilities:

- Implement new features.
- Be awarded of the application.
- Design and find the best way to solve bugs.
- Deploy and testing docker image.
- Be responsible for 6 team members.
- Code reviewing.

Technologies: Git, AWS, Java, JavaScript, React, MySQL, Docker, Rest.

### **December 2020 - March 2022**

### **Senior Java Developer**

### **Company: Globant BBVA**

### Responsibilities:

- Version control of the code with git.
- Consumption of APIS using Rest.
- Implementation of unit tests and integration tests.
- Use the SonarQube plugin to improve code quality and maintain good practices.
- Application setup locally using docker.
- Build and deploy versions of applications in Jenkins.
- Code reviewing.

**Technologies**: Git, APIs, Rest, Jenkins, Java, Spring Boot

### <u>December 2018 – December 2020</u>

#### **Software Developer**

### **Company: Ceiba Software Suramericana de seguros**

### Responsibilities:

- Responsible for the correct development of new requirements for the correct issuance of policies.
- Version control of the code with git
- Creation and use of microservices.
- Consumption of APIS using Rest.
- Implementation of unit tests and integration tests.
- Use of the SonarQube plugin to improve code quality and maintain good practices.
- Component creation and reuse.
- Build and deploy versions of applications in Jenkins.
- Structuring of exportable documents.
- Support the incident team.

Technologies: Git, APIs, Rest, Java, Scala, Angular, Gosu, Jenkins,

# **April 2018 – December 2018**

### **Backend Developer**

**Company: Smile Solutions S.A** 

# Responsibilities:

- worked on the development of POS software.
- Using Hibernate.
- Implementation of unit tests and integration tests.
- Use of the SonarQube plugin to improve code quality and maintain.
- good practices.
- Component creation and reuse.
- Build and deploy versions of applications in Jenkins.
- Structuring of exportable documents.

**Technologies**: Hibernates, Jenkins, Java, Spring Boot